Guide to the Bill Ryan papers, 1932-1989 MS2141.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Bill Ryan papers
1932-1989
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Ryan, Bill
MS2141.UA
4 Linear Feet
Collection consists of blankets, a football helmet, an athletic letter, a football, football programs, a pennant from 1957 Sun Bowl game, scrapbooks, photos, cups, and a trophy donated by Bill Ryan. Bill Ryan earned an A.A. degree from George Washington University in 1934 and also served as President of Colonials, Inc. athletic booster club in 1956-1957.
Box 3
Box 1
Box 2
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated by Bill Ryan to University Archives in 2000.
Biographical Note
Bill Ryan earned an A.A. degree from George Washington University in 1934 and also served as President of Colonials, Inc. athletic booster club in 1956-57.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection consists of blankets, a football helmet, an athletic letter, a football, football programs, a pennant from 1957 Sun Bowl game, scrapbooks, photos, cups, and a trophy. The collection ranges in date from 1932-89.
Helmets; Football; Scrapbooks; Sports; Washington (D.C.); George Washington University; George Washington University--Alumni and alumnae; Ryan, Bill
- 2 blankets, 1950 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  General note
  [From original finding aid]: - one with GW athletic letter, "1951-52-53 Co-Capt." lettering, and GW seal
- Pennant from 1957 Sun Bowl game (Box 1, Folder 2)
- GW athletic letter, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Game ball from 1946 GW football game with player's signatures (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Football helmet, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Framed certificate to Bill Ryan as member of GW football team, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- T-shirt "Colonials", undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Scrapbook, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  [From original finding aid]: - photos of old GW football players and autographs, clippings, Alumni Reunion newsletters, By-Laws of "Colonials, Inc." and lists of members
- Scrapbook, 1977-1983 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  [From original finding aid]: - photos of GW "Varsity House" reunion, list of 1982-83 Colonials, Inc. Board of Trustees, members list 1977-78
- Pack of photos, 1989 ca. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Scrapbook, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  [From original finding aid]: - "Colonials, Inc." (Bill Ryan, president 1957-58), and other correspondence
- Scrapbook - 1957 Sun Bowl team reunion (Box 2, Folder 5)
- GW Hatchets, 1948-1956 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  [From original finding aid]: - 2 from 1948, 1 from 1956, announcing GW Sun Bowl invitation
- Sports Awards programs, 1961-1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Football program, 11/04/1932 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Football program, 11/1932 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  [Thanksgiving Day]
- Football program, 10/11/1946 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Football program, 10/01/1955 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Football program Sun Bowl game, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Football program, 11/24/1966 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Trophy, 1952-1955 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  [From origina finding aid]: - "Awarded to Bill Ryan for Outstanding Support and Friendship, 1952-1955" presented by the GW football team
- Mug - GW Colonials, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Mug - Alumni Reunion, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Glass mug - GW seal, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Ash tray - GWU, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Stein - GWU lettering and seal, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Alumni Service Award, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  [From original finding aid]: - William F. Ryan, Jr. (A.A. 1934)